Register to the Papers of Kurt Weill and Lotte Lenya
Yale University Music Library
- Arrangements for Lenya, 1929-1965; Series II; 5.4' (10 boxes)
  - Music by Weill, II.A
    - Songs, II.A.4
      - [Walt Whitman songs. Beat! Beat! Drums; arr.] No. 2: Beat! Beat! Drum / Kurt Weill; Walt Whitman., 21 parts; 32 cm. (Box 44, Folder 116)
        Includes flute I-II, oboe, clarinet I-II, bass clarinet, bassoon, horn I-II, trumpet I-II, trombone I-II, harp, timpani, military drums, violin I (8), violin II (7), viola (6), violoncello (5), double bass (4) parts.
        "From the Rental Library of Chappell & Co., Inc." - old folder.
      - [Walt Whitman songs. Dirge for two veterans; arr.] Dirge for two veterans., 1 score (18 p.); 43 cm. (Box 106, Folder 117)
        Manuscript in ink with blue and red pencil additions.
      - [Walt Whitman songs. Dirge for two veterans; arr.] Dirge for two veterans., 16 parts; 32 cm. (Box 45, Folder 118)
        Includes piano-conductor (original and 2 copies), harp or piano, reeds I-IV (flute (2), oboe, clarinet), trumpet I-II, trombone, guitar (tacet), percussion, violin A-C, viola, violoncello, and double bass parts.
        "Higher key (3 flats) not used at Carnegie 2/15/59" - on old envelope.
      - [Walt Whitman songs. Dirge for two veterans; arr.] Dirge for two veterans: low key., 17 parts; 32 cm. (Box 45, Folder 119)
        Includes piano-conductor (original and 2 copies), harp or piano, reeds I-IV (flute, clarinet, oboe, clarinet), trumpet I-II, trombone, percussion, violin A-C (original and 3 copies), viola, violoncello, double bass, and guitar (tacet) parts.
        Copies of original piano-conductor and violin part in another folder.
        "Low key (5 flats) / Carnegie Concert 2/15/59" - old envelope.
      - [Walt Whitman songs. Dirge for two veterans; arr.] No. 3: Dirge for two veterans., 21 parts; 32 cm. (Box 45, Folder 120)
        Includes flute I-II, oboe, clarinet I-II, bass clarinet, bassoon, horn I-II, trumpet I-II, trombone I-II, percussion (2), harp, violin I (8), violin II (7), viola (6), violoncello (5), and double bass (5) parts.
        "From the Rental Library of Chappell & Co., Inc...." - stamped on parts.
        "(C) Orig." - old folder.
      - [Walt Whitman songs. Dirge for two veterans; arr.] No. 3: Dirge for two veterans: (key of A) / Kurt Weill., 20 parts; 32 cm. (Box 45, Folder 121)
        Includes flute I-II, oboe/English horn, clarinet I-II, bass clarinet, bassoon, horn I-II, trumpet I-II, trombone I-II, percussion (3), harp, violin I (8), violin II (7), viola (6), violoncello (5), and double bass (4).
        "From the Rental Library of Chappell & Co., Inc...." - stamped on each part.
      - [Walt Whitman songs. Oh captain! My captain; arr.] Oh Captain! My captain / Kurt Weill; Walt Whitman., 1 score (21 p.); 43 cm. (Box 106, Folder 122)
        Manuscript in ink with additions in red pencil and words in blue ink.
      - [Walt Whitman songs. Oh captain! My captain; arr.] Oh captain! My captain., 14 parts; 32 cm. (Box 45, Folder 123)
        Includes piano-conductor (original and 2 copies), harp or piano, reeds (flute, clarinet (2), bass clarinet), trumpet I-II, trombone, guitar, percussion, violin A-C (original and 3 copies), viola, violoncello, and double bass parts.
        "Higher key (2 flats) / Phil Long re-orchestration" - old envelope.
      - [Walt Whitman songs. Oh captain! My captain; arr.] Oh captain! My captain: Low key., 15 parts; 32 cm. (Box 45, Folder 124)
        Includes piano-conductor (original and 2 copies), piano or harp, reeds I-IV (flute, clarinet (2), bass clarinet), trumpet I-II, trombone I, percussion, violin (original and 3 copies), viola, violoncello, double bass, and guitar parts.
        "Low key (4 flats) / Carnegie Concert 2/15/59" - old envelope.
      - [Walt Whitman songs. Oh captain! My captain; arr.] No. 1: Oh captain! My captain / Kurt Weill; Walt Whitman., 21 parts; 32 cm. (Box 45, Folder 125)
        Includes flute I-II, oboe, clarinet I-II, bass clarinet, bassoon, horn I-II, trumpet I-II, trombone I-II, harp, percussion (2), violin I (8), violin II (7), viola (6), violoncello (5), and double bass (4) parts.
        "F orig" - old folder.
        "From the Rental Library of Chappell & Co., Inc." - stamped on parts.
  - Music by Others, II.B
    - [Young blood] Young blood., Cacavas, John; 1 part ([3] p.); 32 cm. (Box 46, Folder 126)
      "Lenya" on p. [1].
    - [Mutter Courage und Ihre Kinder. Selections; arr.], Dessau, Paul; 6 scores; 34 cm. (Box 46, Folder 127)
      Words by Bertolt Brecht, all but "Song from Mother Courage" are an English translation.
      Contents: Song from Mother Courage ([4] p., 3 copies, 1 negative). Song of the great capitulation (3 p., 2 copies). Song of Mother Goose: prologue (3 p., 2 copies). Wise woman and the soldier (4 p., incomplete). Lullaby ([1] sheet). Song of Fraternization (3 p.).
    - [Mutter Courage und Ihre Kinder. Selections; arr.], [9] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 46, Folder 127)
      Guitar part?.
      Contents: I-II. Song of Mother Courage. III. 2nd scene: Song of the woman and soldier. IV. 3rd scene: The song of fraternization.
    - [Ballade vom Weib und dem Soldaten. English [?]] Ballad of the soldier's wife / Eisler; Brecht-Tabori., Eisler, Banns; 1 score (5 p.); 34 cm. (Box 46, Folder 128)
    - [Ballade von der Judenhure Marie Sanders. English] Ballad of Marie Sanders, the Jewish girl / Eisler; Brecht-Tabori., 1 score (3 p.); 32-36 cm. (Box 46, Folder 128)
      Manuscript (photocopies) with ink and pencil additions.
    - [Lied von der Moldau. English] Waters of the Moldau / Eisler; Brecht-Tabori., 1 score (4 sheets); 32 cm. (Box 46, Folder 128)
    - [Mutter. English [?]] Song of a German Mother / Eisler; Brecht., 1 score [2] sheets); 32-36 cm. (Box 46, Folder 128)
    - [Radwechsel] Radwechsel / Gedicht von Bert Brecht, 1960 Jul. 9-10.; Halle, Friedrich Ebert; 1 score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 46, Folder 129)
      At end: Hamburg - Friedrich Ebert Halle - July 9/10, 1960.
    - [Last triangle. Last laugh] Last laugh., Horak, Alexander; 1 score (pp. 9-11); 35 cm. (Box 46, Folder 130)
      Manuscript (photocopy) signed by Horak.
      For voice, piano (2), and accordion.
      Copy of typed letter, signed to Lenya from Horak (1964 Jun. 2) laid in, original is with correspondence.
    - [Last triangle. Last laugh. Vocal score] Last laugh: from The last triangle / A. Horak., 1 vocal score ([2] p.); 36 cm. (Box 46, Folder 130)
      Manuscript signed (photocopy).
    - [Cabaret. What would you do; arr. Vocal score] What would you do: from new musical "Cabaret" John Kander; Fred Ebb. - [New York: Sunbeam Music Corp. [?]], c1966., Kander, John; 1 vocal score (7 p.); 32 cm. (Box 46, Folder 131)
  - Unidentified works, II.C
    - Good woman (Sketches), [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 46, Folder 132)
      English translation of Brecht's German text?.
    - In memory of Marie A. / Brecht-Tabori., 1 score (3 p.); 33 cm. (Box 46, Folder 132)
      Incomplete copy laid in.
    - Party, 1 score (13 [i.e. 10] p.); 32 cm. (Box 46, Folder 132)
    - Some stories about Herr Kauner. Text, [1] sheet; 29 cm. (Box 46, Folder 132)
      Typescript pasted on cardboard.
      From Brecht on Brecht?.
- Music by others, 1912-1944; Series III; .4' (1 box)
  Music by others includes holograph, manuscript, and published works. The items are arranged alphabetically by composer. Information concerning uniform titles, cross-references, alphabetization, housing, abbreviations, and box and folder numbers appears in the series description for Series I: MUSIC BY WEILL.
  - [Few little English] Few little English, 1936 Jul. 15.; Blitzstein, Marc, 1905-1964; 1 score (7 p.); 37 cm. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    Holograph [?] in ink with pencil additions.
    On bottom of p. 1: Copyright 1936 by Marc Blitzstein.
    On p. 1 above the vocal line: Lenya.
  - [Brautwahl. Suite] Orchester-Suite aus der Musik zur Oper "die Brautwahl" / von Ferruccio Busoni, 1912 Aug.; Busoni, Ferruccio, 1866-1924; 1 score (110 p.); 36 cm. (Box 46, Folder 2)
    Published score pasted on manuscript paper and heavily annotated with many additions, changes, and title page in Busoni's hand [?].
    On title page: Fünf Stücke: 1. Spukhaftes. 2. Lyrisches. 3. Mystisches. 4. Hebraeisches. 5. Heiteres.
    On p. 1: Ferruccio Busoni (August, 1912).
    Dedication to Kurt Weill on title page.
    Notes ([2] sheets) found laid in between pp. 83-84.
    See also: I. MUSIC BY WEILL. F. Songs. Frauentanz, no. 3; arr. Vocal score.
  - [Second hurricane. Vocal score] Second hurricane: a play-opera for high school performance / music by Aaron Copland; libretto by Edwin Denby. - Boston: C. C. Birchard, c1938., Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990; 1 vocal score (112 p.); 27 cm. (Box 46, Folder 3)
    Inscription to Kurt Weill and Lenya from Denby on title page.
  - [Odeurs. Nr. 1] Odeurs: 3 couplets., Guilbert, Yvette, 1865-1944; 1 score ([2] p.); 35 cm. (Box 46, Folder 4)
    Holograph [?].
  - [Odeurs. Text], [3] sheets; 21 x 21 cm. (Box 46, Folder 4)
    Typescript signed by and with notes by Guilbert.
    See also: I. MUSIC BY WEILL. A. Operas, Operettas, Musicals, and Ballets. Dreigroschenoper. Pauv' Madam' Peachum. Vocal score. French.
  - [Fièvre Jaune. Polyglot] Fièvre Jaune = Yellow fever = Gelbes Fieber / musique de A. Honegger; poésie de Nino; traduction allemande de Hansi Gosselin; traduction anglaise de Yvonne Deneufville. - Paris: Sirène Musicale, c1935., Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955; 1 score (4 p.); 35 cm. (Box 46, Folder 5)
    Unsigned inscription on p. 1.
  - [Chant de la libération] Chant de la libération / paroles et musique de Anna Marly. - [New York: France Music], c1944., Marly, Anna, 1917-2006; 1 score ([1] folded sheet); 25 x 40 cm. (Box 46, Folder 6)
    Manuscript [in copyist's hand?] with typescript words (photocopy).
    Pl. no.: F. 810. M.
    See also: I. MUSIC BY WEILL. B. Film scores. Salute to France. Chant de la libération; arr. (Sketches).
  - [Médée. Vocal score] Médée: opéra en trois tableaux / musique de Darius Milhaud; livret de Madeleine Milhaud. - Paris: Heugel, c1939., Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974; 1 score (116 p.); 29 cm. (Box 46, Folder 7)
    Inscription to Kurt Weill from Darius and Madeleine Milhaud on front fly leaf.
  - [?], [n.d.]; Weill, Albert; [1] sheet of music; 22 x 28 cm. (Box 46, Folder 8)
    Holograph in ink (photocopy).
    Unaccompanied melody.
    Four verses written beneath melody with first verse.
- Correspondence, 1911-1980; Series IV; 2.1' (6 boxes)
  Correspondence is divided into eleven subseries which are arranged alphabetically by sender or recipient except for the last five subseries, which are arranged chronologically. Cross-references are provided for variant forms of names, from individuals to corporate bodies or vice versa, and for enclosures. Enclosures are counted among the number of items. Restricted items which are housed either at the Music Library or at the Kurt Weill Foundation are indicated as such in the register. Permission to see these items must be obtained from the Kurt Weill Foundation.
  - Drafts of Letters from Weill to Others, IV.A
    See also: F. Weill Family Correspondence.
    - A. & S. Lyons, 1941 Oct. 3; 1 item. (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Abravanel, Maurice, 1948 Dec. 29; 2 items.
    - Allenberg, Bert, 1938 Mar. 31; 2 items.
      See also: Wanger, Walter.
    - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers, [ca. 1945]; 1 item.
    - Aufricht, [Ernst Josef], 1937 Aug. 10; 1 item.
    - Austin, A. Everett, 1936 Jan. 15; 1 item.
    - Ballo, Fernando, 1948 Dec. 29; 1 item. (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Behrman, Sam, 1939-1942; 4 items.
    - Bekker, ?, n.d.; 1 item.
      Copy.
    - Blitzstein, Kara, 1942 Apr. 27; 1 item.
    - Borchardt, [Hans], 1941 Aug. 12; 1 item.
    - Brandt & Brandt Dramatic Department
      See: Freedman, Harold.
    - Brecht, Bertolt, 1939-1950; 15 items.
      See also: Felix Bloch Erben.
    - Brown, James L., 1945 Aug. 31; 1 item.
    - Cohen, Henry, 1936 Mar. 13; 1 item. (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Collins, Alan C., 1942 Nov. 17; 1 item.
    - Cowan, Lester, 1947 Jun. 26; 1 item.
    - Crawford, Cheryl, 1944 Jan.-Sep.; 2 items.
    - Crouse, Russell, 1942 Sep. 30; 1 item.
    - [Dalrymple], Jean, 1943 Nov. 17; 1 item.
    - Dietrich, Marlene, 1934-1942; 3 items. (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Downes, Olin, 1949 Nov. 14; 1 item.
    - Dreyfus, Max, 1936-1947; 5 items.
    - [Eitington], Motty, 1937 Feb. 6; 1 item.
    - Eternal Road Distributing Company, 1936 Oct. 9; 1 item.
    - Eternal Road Inc., 1937 Jan. 14; 1 item.
    - Etkins, Irene, 1947 Jul. 25; 1 item.
    - Felix Bloch Erben, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Fitelson Mayers and London, 1948 Jan. 16; 1 item.
    - Fontanne, Lynn, 1939 Nov. 5; 1 item.
    - Frank, Bruno, 1940 Jun. 17; 1 item.
    - Freedman, Harold, 1936 Jul. 11; 1 item.
    - Gershwin, Ira, 1940-1944; 10 items. (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Gheraldi, M. Ugo, 1938-1939; 5 items. (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Goldman, Louis L., 1944 Apr. 12; 1 item.
    - Gordon, Max, 1944 Aug.-Oct.; 2 items.
    - Green, Paul, 1937 Aug.-Oct.; 2 items.
    - Gutheim, Karlheinz, 1949 Jan. 31; 1 item.
    - Guthrie, ?, 1942 May 9; 1 item.
    - Heinsheimer, Hans W., 1941-1949; 3 items. (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Henry, William J., 1950 Jan. 28; 1 item.
    - Heugel, 1936-1937; 3 items.
    - Heumann, 1949 Dec. 3; 1 item.
    - Horowitz, Jack E. [accountant], 1942-1947; 9 items.
    - [Hughes], Langston, 1946 Jan.-Sep.; 3 items. (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Jeliffe, Smith Ely, 1950 Feb. 11; 1 item. (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Jenkins, ?, 1948 Jul. 11; 1 item.
    - Kommer, [Rudolf K.], 1935 Jan. 15; 1 item.
    - Korda, Sir Alexander, 1948 Dec. 11; 1 item.
    - [Lawrence], Gertrude, 1947 Oct. 11; 1 item. (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Lazar, Irving, 1945-1948; 10 items.
    - Leavitt, Max, 1949 Jun. 29; 1 item.
    - Lennihan, ?, 1941 Jun. 16; 1 item.
    - Lerner, Alan [Jay], 1949 Jan.-Apr.; 2 items.
    - Lewis, Robert, 1941 May 5; 1 item.
    - Lewis, Russell, 1942 Nov. 14; 1 item.
    - Lieber, Maxim, 1947 Apr. 27; 1 item.
    - Life, 1947 Feb. 21; 1 item.
    - [Lunt], Alfred, 1939 Oct. 7; 1 item.
    - Lyons, Arthur, 1939-1947; 17 items. (Box 47, Folder 10)
      See also: A. & S. Lyons.
    - McArthur, Charles, 1946 Jan. 21; 1 item. (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - [MacLeish], Archibald, 1942 Jun. 9; 1 item.
    - Mamoulian, Rouben, 1946 Jan. 22; 1 item.
    - Madden, Richard, 1941-1943; 2 items.
    - Mann, Erika, 1940 Jun. 17; 1 item.
    - Marton, George, 1942 Mar. -Apr.; 3 items.
    - Meredith, Burgess, n.d.; 1 item.
    - Meyer, Mr., 1943 Dec. 2; 1 item.
    - Meyer, Mrs. [Eugene], 1936 Mar. 8; 1 item.
    - Milestone, Lewis, 1944 May 19; 1 item.
    - [Morros], Boris, 1938 Mar. 17; 1 item.
    - Muse, Clarence, 1942 Mar.-Apr.; 2 items.
    - [Nash], Ogden, 1947 Dec. 19; 1 item. (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Nizer, Louis, 1937 Feb.-Apr.; 4 items.
    - [Page], Ruth, 1939 Oct. 25; 1 item.
    - Paine, John G., 1939 Mar.-May; 3 items.
    - Perelman, S. J., 1943 Nov. 12; 1 item.
    - Rapport, Victor A., 1947 Sep. 30; 1 item. (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Reinhardt, Max, 1934-1936; 5 items.
    - Reinheimer, Howard, 1942-1947; 2 items.
    - Robeson, [Eslanda Goode] (Mrs. Paul), 1942 Jun. 11; 1 item.
    - Ronnell, Ann, 1948 Feb. 4; 1 item.
    - Sablosky, Mr., 1948 Jul. 24; 1 item. (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Salisbury, Leah, 1943-1944; 8 items.
    - Samrock, Victor, 1939-1950; 4 items.
    - Saroyan, [William], 1947 n. m. 28; 1 item.
    - Sharaff, Irene, 1942-1943; 3 items.
    - Société Italienne des Auteurs et Editeurs, 1938 Mar.; 1 item.
    - Speiser, Maurice, 1939-1944; 5 items.
    - Spier, Larry, 1949 Dec. 19; 1 item.
    - Stegman, G.F., 1949 Feb. 14; 1 item.
    - Sternberg, ?, 1934 Mar. 6-24; 3 items.
      See also: Dietrich, Marlene.
    - Stewart, Rosalee, 1942 Jan. 22; 1 item.
    - Stokowski, [Leopold], 1935 Sep. 12; 1 item.
    - Street Scene Company, 1947 Jan. 9; 1 item.
    - [Sundgaard], Arnold, 1949 Aug. 10; 1 item.
    - Universal Edition
      See: Felix Bloch Erben.
    - United States. Department of Justice. Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1943 Apr. 5; 1 item. (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - [Vincent], Allen, 1942 Jan. 22; 1 item.
    - Wanger, Walter, 1938 Apr. 8; 1 item.
    - Watt, Doug, 1950 Jan. 13; 1 item.
    - Wechsler, Herbert, 1943 Jan. -Mar.; 3 items.
    - Weisgal, Meyer, 1936-1937; 2 items.
    - Werfel, Alma Maria, 1937 Mar. 1; 1 item.
    - Werfel, Franz, 1936 Aug. 3; 1 item.
    - Wharton, John F., 1939-1947; 5 items.
    - Wilder, [Isabel], 1947 Apr. 7; 1 item.
    - Wise, Ronald, 1942 Apr. 11; 1 item.
    - [Wolpin], Eddie, 1943 Nov, 30; 1 item.
    - Wood, [Audrey], 1941-1949; 2 items.
    - Yannopoulous, Dino, 1949 Nov. 12; 1 item.
    - Western Union Book, 1 item; 15 p.; 14-22 cm. (Box 47, Folder 16)
      Containing original copies and sketches of Kurt Weill's telegrams to others.
      Includes telegrams to: Kenny Baker, Cheryl Crawford, Ira Gershwin, Teddy Hart, Jack E. Horowitz, Paul Kohner, Alexander Korda, Irving Lazar, Mary Martin, Lewis Milestone, Sid Perelman, Mrs. Max Reinhardt, Billy Rose, Leah Salisbury, Irene Sharaff, Maurice Speiser, Larry Spier, and Eddie Wolpin with copy of telegram from Elia Kazan.
      Loose sheets (22 p.) laid in.
    - ?, "Bob", 1941 Dec. 12; 1 item. (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence - To Weill, IV.B
    - ASCAP, 1938-1945; 5 items. (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - [Abravanel], Maurice, n.d.; 5 items.
    - Adorno, Theodore W., 1942 Mar. 31; 1 item.
      Includes 2 signed agreements.
    - Allenberg, Bert, 1938 Apr. -Oct.; 4 items.
    - American Committee for the Weizmann Institute of Science
      See: Weisgal, Meyer.
    - Anderson, Maxwell, 1938-1948; 6 items. (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Antheil, George, 1949 Nov. 18; 1 item.
    - Atkinson, Brooks, 1949-1950; 2 items.
    - Aucoin, Lionel A., 1945 Jul.-Aug.; 2 items.
    - Aufricht, Ernst Josef, 1937-1943; 2 items.
    - [Aufricht?], Margot, 1947 Jan. 9; 1 item.
    - Ballard, Lucinda, 1947 Jan. 9; 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - Ballo, Fernando, 1938-1949; 2 items.
    - Barry, Philip, 1936 Nov. 19; 1 item.
    - [Behrman], Sam, 1939-1942; 5 items.
    - Bergman, Ingrid, 1947 Jan. 9; 1 item.
    - Berlin, Irving, 1949 Jul. 18; 1 item.
    - Berliner Ensemble, 1949 Sep. 27; 1 item.
    - Bettelheim, Max G., 1948 Sep. 5; 1 item.
    - Blitzstein, Marc, 1936-1949; 4 items.
    - Borchardt, Hermann H., 1940-1941; 10 items. (Box 48, Folder 21)
      Includes copies of letters to Borchardt from R. K. Kommer and from Borchardt to Archibald MacLeish, as well as writings by Borchardt and Thornton Wilder.
    - Brecht, Bertolt, 1939-1947; 11 items. (Box 48, Folder 22)
      Includes typescript of poem entitled "Deutschland."
    - Brookings Institution, 1941 May 1; 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Byram, John, 1943-1947; 3 items.
    - Chapman, John, 1950 Jan. 6; 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - Chappell & Co., 1943-1944; 10 items.
      See also: Sirmay, Albert.
    - Clurman, Harold, 1936 Nov. 19; 1 item.
    - [Cocteau], Jean, 1933 Apr. -Dec.; 4 items. (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - Cowan, Lester, 1948 Jan. 19; 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 26)
    - Crawford, Cheryl, 1943-1947; 16 items.
      Includes typed letter, signed from Richard Rodgers to Crawford.
    - Crouse, Russell, 1938-1943; 6 items. (Box 48, Folder 27)
    - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1942 Nov. 13; 1 item.
    - Dalrymple, Jean, 1944 Jan. 27; 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 28)
    - Decca Records, 1944 Jan. 4; 1 item.
    - De Mille, Agnes, 1943 Jul. 11-22; 4 items.
    - Deval, Jacques, n.d.; 1 item.
      Poem enclosed.
    - Dietrich, Marlene, 1934 Mar. 3; 3 items. (Box 48, Folder 29)
      Includes 2 typescript copies of telegrams.
    - Downes, Olin, 1941-1949; 2 items.
    - Dramatists' Guild, 1942 Oct. 9-14; 2 items.
    - Dreyfus, Louis, 1950 Jan. 17; 2 items.
      Typed letter, signed to Dreyfus enclosed.
    - Dreyfus, Max, 1943-1949; 5 items.
      See also: Chappell & Co.
    - Duke, Vernon, ca. 1941 Jan.; 1 item.
    - Duncan, Todd, 1949 Aug. 29; 1 item.
    - Einstein, Albert, 1936-1938; 2 items. (Box 48, Folder 30)
      Translation laid in.
    - Eternal Road Distributing Company, 1936 Dec. 2; 1 item.
    - Etkin, Irene
      See: Lyons, Arthur.
    - Evans, Graham, 1954 Jun. 14; 1 item.
    - Felix Bloch Erben, 1949 Jul. 11; 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 31)
    - Field, Betty, 1949 Oct. 30; 1 item.
    - Fields, Herbert and Dorothy, 1947-1949; 2 items.
    - Fontanne, Lynn, 1939 Oct. 17; 1 item.
    - Ford, Ellen M., 1944 Jan. 24; 1 item.
    - Frank, Bruno, 1940 Apr. -Jul.; 3 items.
    - Freedman, Harold, 1939 Jul. 25; 1 item.
    - Friedman, Charles, 1947 Jan. 9; 1 item.
    - Gauty, Lys, 1936 Jul. 6; 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 32)
    - Geis, Jakob, 1949 Jan. 3; 1 item.
    - George, Manfred, 1943 Apr. 5; 1 item.
    - Gershwin, Ira, 1936-1945; 29 items. (Box 48, Folder 33)
      Includes letter from William Perlberg to Gershwin.
    - Gershwin, Rose, 1941 Jan. 23; 1 item.
    - Gheraldi, Ugo, 1938-1939; 12 items. (Box 48, Folder 34)
    - Gilson, Henry, 1949 Nov. 2; 1 item.
    - Goldie, William V., 1949 Oct. 30; 1 item.
    - Goldmark, Colin and Kaye, 1943 May 3; 1 item.
    - Gordon, Max, 1940-1944; 26 items. (Box 48, Folder 35)
      Includes copy of letter to Walter Slezak.
    - Gordon, Paul, 1941 Oct. 27; 1 item.
    - Gould, Morton, 1949 Oct. 30; 1 item.
    - Graf, Herbert, 1949 Mar. 3; 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 36)
    - Green, Paul, 1936-1942; 7 items.
      Includes autograph letter, signed from Paya Haskell to Green.
    - Gregory, Duke, 1944 Mar. 19; 1 item.
    - Grey, Madeleine, 1937 Jun. 29; 1 item.
    - Gutheim, Karlheinz, 1949 Jan. -Feb.; 2 items.
    - [Halliday?], Dick, 1943 Dec. 9; 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 37)
    - Hammerstein, Oscar, 1947 Jan. 20; 1 item.
      See also: Rodgers, Richard.
    - Harris, Jed, n.d.; 1 item.
      See also: Speiser, Maurice.
    - Harris, Sam H., 1941 Mar. -May; 4 items.
    - Hart, Moss and Kitty, 1941-1949; 4 items.
    - Hauptmann, Elisabeth, 1941 Mar. 14; 2 items.
      Bank receipt enclosed.
    - Hayes, Helen, 1942-1947; 3 items.
    - Hayward, Dolores, 1947 Jan. 9; 1 item.
    - Hecht, Rose, 1947 Aug. 21; 1 item.
    - [Helburn], Theresa, 1939 Dec. 19; 1 item.
    - Heugel, ?, 1936 Dec. 9; 1 item.
    - Hoffman, Irving, n.d.; 1 item.
    - Horowitz, Jack E. [accountant], 1942-1947; 27 items. (Box 48, Folder 38)
      See also: D. To Lenya.
    - Howard, Polly, 1941 Apr. 6; 1 item.
    - Hughes, Langston, 1947 Jan.-Apr.; 2 items.
    - Jeffreys, Anne, 1946 Nov. 8; 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 39)
    - John C. Pinto and Associates
      See: Pinto, John C.
    - Jones, Robert Edmond, 1941 Aug. -Sep.; 2 items.
    - [Kaiser], Billa, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 40)
    - Kaiser, Georg, 119321-1938; 8 items.
      Includes postcard to Billa Kaiser.
    - Kaufman, George S., 1945-1947; 5 items. (Box 48, Folder 41)
    - Kazan, Elia, n.d.; 2 items.
    - Kommer, Rudolf K., 1941-1942; 2 items.
    - Korda, Sir Alexander, n.y. Dec. 3; 1 item.
    - Koussevitzky, Serge, 1947 Dec. I; 1 item.
    - Kranzberg, Ann, 1948 Mar. 26; 1 item.
    - Kubik, Gail, 1947 Jul. 26; 1 item.
    - Lane, Burton, 1949 Oct. 30; 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 42)
    - Lawrence, Gertrude, 1940-1950; 8 items.
    - Lawrence, Robert, n.y. Sep. 6; 1 item.
    - Lazar, Irving, 1945-1948; 20 items. (Box 48, Folder 43)
    - Le Corbusier, 1932 Dec. 13; 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 44)
    - Lenihan, Winifred, 1941 Jun. 17; 1 item.
    - Lerner, Alan Jay, n.d.; 1 item.
    - Lerner, Marion Bell, 1949 Oct. 30; 1 item.
    - Levine, Maurice, 1935 Dec. 13; 1 item.
    - Levinger, Henry W., 1948 Feb. 29; 1 item.
    - Lewis, Russell, 1942 Nov. -Dec.; 3 items.
    - Lieber, Maxim, 1947 Apr. 22; 1 item.
      See also: Hughes, Langston.